when you boost a neural network one of
当你在使用一个神经网络的时候
the choices you get to make is what
你需要做一个选择 来决定
activation functions to use in the hidden
哪一种激活函数用在你的神经网络的
layers as well as at the output unit of
隐藏层上 哪一种用在输出节点上
your neural network so far we've just
到目前为止 我们只
been using the sigmoid activation
用过sigmoid激活函数
function but sometimes other choices can
但是 其他的激活函数有时
work much better let's take a look at
效果会更好 让我们来看一下
some of the options in the forward
一些可选的激活函数 在神经网路的
propagation steps for the neural network
前向传播中
we have these two steps where we use the
我们执行这两步 在这里我们会使用
sigmoid function here so that sigmoid is
sigmoid函数
called an activation function and here is
sigmoid函数被称为激活函数 这里
the familiar sigmoid function a equals 1
是熟悉的sigmoid函数 a 等于 1 除以
over 1 plus e to negative z so in the
1 加上 e 的 -z 次 所以在
more general case we can have a
更通常的情况下 我们可以使用
different function g of Z which I gonna write
不同的函数 g（Z) 我写在这
here where G could be a nonlinear
这里，g可以是一个非线性函数
function that may not be the sigmoid
可能不是sigmoid函数
function so for example the sigmoid
比如说 sigmoid函数
function goes between 0 & 1 an
的值在0和1之间
activation function that almost always
一个总体上都优于sigmoid函数的
works better than the sigmoid function
激活函数
is the tanh function or the hyperbolic
是tanh函数 或者双曲正切函数
tangent function so this is Z this is a
这是Z 这是a
this is a equals tanh of Z and this goes
a 等于tanh(Z)
between plus 1 and minus 1 the formula
函数的值 位于+1和-1之间
for the tanh function is e to the Z minus
tanh函数的公式是 e的z次 减去
e to negative z over there sum and it's
e的-z次 除以两者的和
actually mathematically a shifted
tanh函数事实上是sigmoid的
version of the sigmoid function so as a
一个数学变换形式
you know sigmoid function just like that
sigmoid函数的图像就是这样
but shift it so that it now crosses a
但是对它进行了变换 现在穿过了
zero zero point and rescale so it goes
(0,0)点 再重新缩放之后 它的值
to between minus one and plus one and it turns
介于+1 和 -1之间
out that for hidden units if you let the
结果表明 如果你在隐藏层上
function G of Z be equal to
使用函数g(z)=tanh(z)
tenh（z） this almost always works better
效果总是优于
than the sigmoid function because with
sigmoid函数 因为
values between plus one and minus one
函数值在-1 和 +1 这个区间
the mean of the activations that come
你的脑海中马上就可以想到
out of your head in there are closer to
激活函数的均值是更接近
having a zero mean and so just as
零均值的 也就像有时候
sometimes when you train a learning
当你在训练一个
algorithm
算法
you might Center the data and have your
你或许会中心化你的数据 使你的数据
data have zero mean using a tanh instead
零均值 使用tanh函数而不是
of a sigmoid function kind of has the
sigmoid函数 某种程度上
effect of centering your data so that
对你中心化数据有影响
the mean of the data is close to the
使得数据的平均值更接近0
zero rather than maybe a 0.5 and this
而不是0.5
actually makes learning for the next
这样的话 会使下一层学习
layer a little bit easier we'll say more
简单一点 我们会在
about this in the second course when we
第二门课中将更多 当我们在
talk about optimization algorithms as
讨论优化算法的时候
well but one takeaway is that I pretty
但是有一点要说明
much never use the sigmoid activation
我基本已经不用sigmoid激活函数了
function anymore
the tanh function is almost always
tanh函数总是
strictly superior the one exception is
严格优秀于sigmoid函数 一个例外是
for the output layer because if Y is
对于输出层 因为Y的值
either 0 or 1 then it makes sense for y
是 0 或 1 所以你想让y(hat)
hat to be a number that you want to
的数值
output that between 0 and 1 rather than
介于0和1之间
between minus 1 and 1 so the one
而不是在-1和+1之间 所以
exception where I would use the sigmoid
我会使用sigmoid激活函数的
activation function is when you're using
一个例外是 当你在做
binary classification in which case you
二分类的问题 这个情况下
might use the sigmoid activation
可能会对输出层使用sigmoid激活函数
function for the output layer so g of Z
所以 在这里的
2 here is equal to Sigma of Z 2 and so
g(Z2) 是等于 sigmoid（Z2）
what you see in this example is where
你在这个例子里看到的是
you might have a tenh activation
你可能会对隐藏层使用
function for the hidden layer and
tanh激活函数
sigmoid for the output layer so the
输出层使用sigmoid函数
activation functions can be different
所以在不同的神经网络层中
for different layers and sometimes to
激活函数可以不同 有时候
denote that the activation functions are
为了表示不同的激活函数
different for different layers we might
使用在不同的层中 我们可能会用
use these square brackets super scripts
方括号上标
as well to indicate that G of square
来指出g上标为[1]的激活函数
bracket 1 may be different than G square
可能会跟g上标为[2]
bracket 2 right again square bracket 1
不同 方括号上标[1]
superscript refers to this layer and
代表这一层
superscript square bracket 2 refers to
方括号上标[2]
the output layer
表示输出层
now one of the downsides of both the
sigmoid函数和tanh函数两者
sigmoid function and the tanh function is
共同的缺点是
that if Z is either very large or very
在Z特别大
small then the gradient of the
或者特别小的情况下 导数的梯度
derivative or the slope of this function
或者函数的斜率
becomes very small so Z is very large or
会变得特别小 所以在Z特别大或者
Z is very small the slope of the
特别小的情况下 函数的斜率
function you know ends up being close to
最后就会接近于0
zero and so this can slow down gradient
这样会降低梯度下降的速度
descent so one of the chooses that is very
在机器学习另一个很流行的
popular in machine learning is what's
函数 是一种被称为
called the rectified linear unit so the
修正线性单元的函数
ReLu function looks like this and the
ReLu函数图像是这个样子
formula is a equals max of 0 comma Z so
公式是a=max(0,Z)
the derivative is 1 so long as Z is
所以 只要Z是正值的情况下
positive and derivative or the slope is
导数是1 当Z是负值的时候
0 when Z is negative if you're
导数或者梯度是0
implementing this technically the
从技术上来说 当你在使用
derivative when Z is exactly 0 is not
Z的导数时，Z=0的导数
well-defined but when you implement is
并很好的定义 但是当你在电脑上
in the computer the often you get
使用它的时候，通常情况下
exactly the equals 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0 0
都会取到等于0.0000000的值
it is very small so you don't need to
这个值相当小 所以你不需要担心这个值
worry about it in practice you could
在实践中 你可以在
pretend a derivative when Z is equal to
Z是等于0的时候 假设一个导数
0 you can pretend is either 1 or 0 and
你可以假设导数是1或者0
you can work just fine so the fact that
效果都可以
is not differentiable the fact that so
事实是两者并没有什么区别
here are some rules of thumb for
这有一些选择激活函数的
choosing activation functions if your
经验法则
output is 0 1 value if you're I'm using
如果你的输出是0 1值 如果你在解决
binary classification then the sigmoid
二分类问题 所以 输出层选择sigmoid函数
activation function is very natural for
输出层很自然的选择sigmoid函数
the output layer and then for all other
选择sigmoid函数 然后其它的所有单元
units on ReLu or the rectified linear
都选择Relu函数
unit is increasingly the default choice
这是很多激活函数
of activation function so if you're not
的默认选择 所以 如果你并不确定
sure what to use for your hidden layer
在隐藏层上 使用哪个激活函数
I would just use the relu activation
我通常会使用Relu激活函数
function that's what you see most people
这也是现在 大多数人
using these days although sometimes
都会使用的函数
people also use the tanh activation
有时候 人们也会使用tanh激活函数
function
one this advantage of the Relu is that
Relu的一个优点是
the derivative is equal to zero when Z
当Z是负值的时候，导数等于0
is negative in practice this works just
在实践中 效果也可以
fine but there is another version of the
这里也有另一个版本的Relu
value called the leaky ReLu will give
被称为Leaky Relu 下一页中会
you the formula on the next slide but
给出公式
instead of it being zero when Z is
当Z是负值时，这个函数的值不是等于0
negative it just takes a slight slope
而是轻微的倾斜
like so so this is called the Leaky
就像这样 这就是Leaky Relu
ReLu this usually works better than the
这个函数通常比ReLu激活函数
Relu activation function although it's
效果要好 尽管在实际中
just not used as much in practice either
Leaky ReLu使用的并不多
one should be fine
两个都可以
although if you had to pick one I
如果你必须要选一个
usually just use the ReLu and the
我通常只使用Relu
advantage of both the ReLu and Leaky
两者的优点是
ReLu is that for a lot of the space of
在Z的区间变动很大的情况下
Z the derivative of the activation
激活函数的导数
function the slope of the activation
或者激活函数的斜率
function is very different from zero and
都会远大于0
so in practice using the ReLu
所以 在实践中 使用
activation function your neural network
ReLu激活函数 你的神经网络
will often learn much faster than using
通常会比使用sigmoid或者tanh激活函数
the ten age or the sigmoid activation
学习的更快
function and the main reason is that on
学习快的主要的原因是
this less of this effect of the slope of
在训练过程中 梯度下降为0从而减慢学习速度
the function going to zero which slows
情况比较少
down learning and I know that for half
我知道Z在ReLu
of the range of Z the slope of relu is
的梯度 一半都是0
zero but in practice enough of your
但是在实际中 你会有足够的
hidden units will have Z greater than
隐藏层 使得你的Z值大于0
zero so learning can still be quite fast
所以对大多数的训练数据来说
for most training examples so let's just
学习过程任然可以很快 所以
quickly recap there are pros and cons of
让我们来快速概括一下 这里有不同激活函数的
different activation functions here's
过程和结论
the sigmoid activation function I would
这是sigmoid激活函数
say never use this except for the output
我基本不会用它 除了输出层
layer if you are doing binary
是一个二分类问题
classification or maybe almost never use
或者 从来不用它
this and the reason I almost never use
我从来不用它的理由是
this is because the tanh is pretty much
因为tanh是非常优秀的
strictly superior so the 10-inch
所以 tanh激活函数
activation function is this and then the
是这样
default the most commonly used
最常见的默认使用
activation function is the ReLu
的激活函数是ReLu
which is this so you're not sure what
是这个样子 如果你不确定用哪个
else to use use this one and maybe you
就使用ReLu
know feel free also to try to leeky ReLu
或者 你也可以试试Leaky ReLu
where um might be
或许是
0.01 Z comma Z right so a is the max of
(0.01Z,Z)这个样子
0.01 times Z and Z so that gives you
a是(0.01Z,Z)的最大值 这会让
this some Bend in the function and you
让函数弯曲
might say you know why is that constant
你或许会问 为什么常数是
0.01 well you can also make that another
0.01 当然
parameter of the learning algorithm and
你也可以为学习算法选择不同的参数
some people say that works even better
有些人说效果会更好
but I hardly see people do that so but
但是我很少见到人们这样做
if you feel like trying it in your
不过你可以在你的应用中试试
application you know please feel free to
请随便试
do so and and you can just see how it
你将会看到
works and how well works and stick with
它是怎么工作的 效果怎么样
it if it gives you good result so I hope
并且坚持这样做，如果这样会给你一个好结果
that gives you a sense of some of the
我希望我讲的东西 让你在选择自己神经网络
choices of activation functions you can
的激活函数时
use in your network one of the themes
有一定的直观感受
we'll see in deep learning is that you
我们在深度学习中的遇到的一个问题是
often have a lot of different choices in
在编写神经网络的时候
how you code your neural network ranging
通常会有很多选择
from number of hidden units to the
从隐藏层单元的个数
chosen activation function to how you
如何选择激活函数
initilize the weights which we'll see
我们将在之后看到的 如何初始化权值
later a lot of choices like that and it
有很多这样的选择
turns out that is sometimes difficult to
这就使得有时候 得到一个对你的问题
get good guidelines for exactly what
比较好的指导原则
will work best for your problem so so
是挺困难的
these three causes I'll keep on giving
鉴于以上三个原因 以及我在工业界的见闻
you a sense of what I see in the
我提供给你们一种直观的感受
industry in terms of what's more or less
哪一种工业界用的多，哪一种用的少
popular but for your application with
但是 对你的应用
your applications video synthesis it's
以及你的应用的特殊性
actually very difficult to know in
所以很难提前知道
advance exactly what will work best so
那些选择的效果更好
common advices would be if you're not
所以通常的建议是 如果你不确定
sure which one of these activation
哪一个激活函数
functions work best you know try them
效果更好 你可以把它们都试试
all and then evaluate on like a holdout
然后在在验证集或者发展集上
validation set or like a development set
进行评价
which we'll talk about later and see
这些以后会讲 然后去看
which one works better and then go of
哪一种表现的更好 就去使用它
that and I think that by testing these
我觉得为你的应用
different choices for your application
测试这些不同的选择
you'd be better at future proofing your
你将会在以后检验
neural network architecture against the
你的神经网络
the distinction sees our problem as well
或者评估算法的时候
evolutions of the algorithms rather than
可以看到不同的效果
you know if I were to tell you always
而不是仅仅遵守 我告诉你的
use a 	ReLu activation and don't use
总是使用ReLu激励函数 而不要用
anything else that that just may or may
其他的激励函数 那就可能
not apply for whatever problem you end
在近期或者往后
up working on you know either
你每次解决问题的时候
either in the near future on the distant
都使用相同的办法
future all right so that was a choice of
好的 这就是
activation functions you've seen the
激活函数的选择 你已经看到了
most popular activation functions
最流行的激活函数
there's one other question that
有一个问题
sometimes is ask which is why do you
时不时被问到 为什么我们
even need to you
需要一个激活函数呢
activation function at all why not just
为什么不
do away with that so let's talk about
直接就那样算呢？
that
让我们在下一个视频中
in the next video and when you see why
讨论这个问题 你将会了解到为什么神经网络
neural network do means some sort of
要需要一系列的
nonlinear activation function
非线性激活函数